SHAHUL HAMEED J

Senior Flutter Developer

Mobile (+91) 7397629607 Email shahul5.it@gmail.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/shahul-hameed-j/ GitHub https://github.com/shahul-hamed

Flutter developer with **4+ years of experience** in Software development. Developed **7+ mobile applications** and contributed in **3+** projects such as **Ecommerce**, **Inventory**, **Employee management** and **Garage management**.

Willingness to take on added responsibilities to **meet team goals**. Ability to handle multiple projects simultaneously with a **high degree of accuracy**. **Expertise in cross platform** mobile application development as well as web application development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Flutter Developer at KAPTAS Technologies

Jun 2022 - Present

- Prototyping and Strong design patterns in mobile applications
- Implement pixel-perfect UI designs
- Implemented comprehensive project management methodologies to drive successful product launches, resulting in a 30% increase in revenue
- Implemented the MVC pattern to streamline code structure, resulting in 40% faster load times and improved scalability for future enhancements
- Implemented Code reusability via widgets customization in all projects
- Effective State management by BLOC, GETX Patterns
- Upgraded Exception Handling that reduces 60 70% bugs
- Clean architecture and implementation of sample test cases
- Ability to implement RESTful API integrations with clear cut functionalities
- Managing code in Git source control
- Experienced in current projects phases using Agile methodologies
- Experienced in managing Google Play and iOS App Store releases

Full Stack Developer at Ad Intra Logs

Nov 2019 - Jun 2022

- RESTful API integrations which were written by back-end services like GRAPHQL, NodeJS and Golang
- Implement pixel-perfect UI designs with responsive
- Maintaining Code Reusability.
- Effective State management by BLOC, GETX Patterns.
- Creating simple REST API including payment integrations using Golang
- Taking ownership of given projects and ensure on time delivery
- Proficiency in version control using GIT
- Experienced in managing Google Play and iOS App Store releases

IT Trainee at IGENIUS Jun 2019 - Nov 2019

- Implementation of job searching web application using Word press.
- Learned HTML and CSS in the short time period and used in the website designs.
- Studied core PHP during the training period and tried to develop simple template design like a Flipkart.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

House of chefs

At House of Chefs, we believe in health is wealth. Home food is always a privilege, especially with 'our hectic life schedules. Here we bring you the home food from House of Chefs without compromising the taste and quality.

Technologies used - Dart, Firebase push notifications, Razor pay, AWS, Laravel.

App link - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.app.hoc_customer

Garage Automate

Automate provides exclusive, tailormade solutions for garage owners to manage their business in smartest way possible. With extensive reports related to operations, productivity, inventory management, accounting etc.

Technologies used - Dart, Firebase Push notifications, AWS, Laravel.

App link - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=in.garagemanagement.automate

Community Aura is redefining Apartment living by providing an easy way to connect, seek and share
information, interact and have fun with your fellow residents. Responsibilities are implementation of
signup with referral contact details. Updating new fields into Fire store collection. Sent mail to admin
using firebase cloud functions with Flutter.

Technologies used - Dart, Firebase push notifications, Firebase Fire store, Firebase Cloud functions, AWS

App link - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.communityaura.social

• **Lightning 360** helps you organize daily work assignments and enables measuring the productivity. Stay informed and connected with all your tasks with real-time status updates on your mobile. Preventive maintenance support and service for assets. Core feature is Asset management and Task management. Technologies used - **Dart, Firebase push notifications, AWS, Spring Boot, NodeJS**.

App link - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=in.lightninglogistics.lltask

Geco FMS is a distributed system developed to maintain the employee details and the company
workflow process systematically. This helps to eliminate the manual process and saves a lot of time and
money. This helps improve employee satisfaction and productivity to help a company achieve their
overall goals.

Technologies used - Dart, Firebase push notifications, Laravel.

App link - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gecogroupindia

Nearle Commerce (Neighborhood commerce)

Great exploration of business from small area to large community. Provides analysis about customers and helps to promote best products to all customers via promotions. Order tracking to make product deliverable. Tenant Live location capturing for providing right service to the right customer at the moment.

Technologies used - Dart, Firebase push notifications, Fire store, Golang, GRAPHQL, Digital Ocean, Docker and Kubernetes.

App link - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nearle.gear

• **Engaje** (Ecommerce Platform)

Engaje allows a local business to engage with their customers effectively. Core features: Ordering, Appointment booking and Handyman service booking. The Engaje app puts the power to support your favorite butcher, baker, café or greengrocer all in the same place.

Technologies used - Dart, Firebase push notifications, Fire store, Golang, GRAPHQL, Digital Ocean, Docker and Kubernetes.

App link - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.engaje.business

TECH SKILLS

- Flutter
- IOS
- Firebase push notifications and Cloud functions
- Payment Gateway Integrations using Stripe and Razor pay
- Proficiency in version control tools: Git, Bitbucket
- Proficiency in Agile tools: JIRA and Trello
- Expertise in REST API and Third Part API Integrations
- State management using GETX, BLOC Pattern and MOBX
- Golang
- Widget testing

- Integration testing
- Unit testing
- CICD (Jenkins)
- React
- HTML
- CSS
- CodeIgniter

SOFT SKILLS

- Collaboration between team members and strong communication
- Adaptability
- Continuous improvement
- Attention to detail
- Time management
- Problem solving ability and logical thinking
- Strong debugging and testing skills.
- Efficient programming skills
- Ensures On time delivery

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Technology, 2015 - 2019

Rathinam Technical Campus, Coimbatore.